Register of the Leopold Labedz papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Printed Matter, 1938-1986
  - "Implementation of the Helsinki Accords,", 1982 September 23 (Box-folder 134: 7)
  - [In Sinhalese], 1960, 1963 (Box-folder 134: 8)
  - "Industrialisierung und Gesellschaft in der Sowjetunion,", 1974 (Box-folder 134: 9)
  - Information Bulletin, 1961 (Box-folder 134: 10)
  - Iniziativa Socialista, 1946 (Box-folder 134: 11)
  - International Front Organisations, 1970 (Box-folder 134: 12)
  - Jesus to the Communist World Inc., pamphlet, 1970 (Box-folder 134: 13)
  - Jews in Eastern Europe, 1960 (Box-folder 134: 14)
  - Kariera Barona Andersona, undated (Box-folder 134: 15)
  - Kochetov, Vsevolod, 1969 (Box-folder 134: 16)
  - Komitet Obrony Robotników, 1976 (Box-folder 134: 17)
  - Leaflets and announcements, circa 1968 (Box-folder 134: 18)
  - Libertà della Cultura, 1969 (Box-folder 134: 19)
  - Lukyx, H., undated (Box-folder 134: 20)
    Hand painted greeting cards.
  - Marine-Rundschau, 1976 (Box-folder 134: 21)
  - "Memorandum: Concerning the Plans of the Soviet Union for the Annexation of Czechoslovakia,", undated (Box-folder 134: 22)
  - Military Review, 1974 (Box-folder 134: 23)
  - Moral Equivalence, 1985 (Box-folder 134: 24)
  - Mówi Warszawa..., undated (Box-folder 134: 25)
  - Myśl Niepodległa, 1985 (Box-folder 134: 26)
  - Na Antenie, 1973 (Box-folder 135: 1)
  - Naprzód, 1969 (Box-folder 135: 2)
  - Nasa rec, 1983 (Box-folder 135: 3)
  - "Negotiation and Statecraft,", 1973 July 12 (Box-folder 135: 4)
  - Neu Beginnen, 1982 (Box-folder 135: 5)
  - The New International, 1982 (Box-folder 135: 6)
  - New Republic, 1947 (Box-folder 135: 7)
  - New Spark, 1948 (Box-folder 135: 8)
  - News Bulletin, No. 66, 1975 (Box-folder 135: 9)
  - News from Hsinhua News Agency, 1965 (Box-folder 135: 10)
  - Niepodległość, 1985 (Box-folder 135: 11)
  - Notes d'Information, 1975 (Box-folder 135: 12)
  - Obraz, 1985 (Box-folder 135: 13)
  - Paris/Prague, 1985 (Box-folder 135: 14)
  - Planning a Network of Retail Stores, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 135: 15)
  - Poems, undated (Box-folder 135: 16)
  - Polish Affairs, 1962 (Box-folder 135: 17)
  - Press releases, 1971, undated (Box-folder 135: 18)
  - Preuves, 1961 (Box-folder 135: 19)
  - Prometeo, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 135: 20)
  - "A Proposed NATO Force Based on the Deployment of Tactical Nuclear Weapons,", 1979 (Box-folder 135: 21)
  - "Report on the Observation of Human Rights and Civil Rights in the Polish People's Republic,", 1980 (Box-folder 135: 22)
  - "Report from Vienna: An Appraisal of the International Peace Academy Committee's 1970 Pilot Project,", 1970 December (Box-folder 135: 23)
  - Rinascita, 1947, 1968 (Box-folder 135: 24)
  - Royal Society of Medicine, 1970 (Box-folder 136: 1)
  - Russia - Soviet Union Communist International, undated (Box-folder 136: 2)
  - Samizdat, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 136: 3)
  - Samostanowienie, 1985 (Box-folder 136: 4)
  - Saturn, 1957 (Box-folder 136: 5)
  - Scientists Committee of the Israel Public Council for Soviet Jews, 1974 (Box-folder 136: 6)
  - "Sicurezza Europea e Alleanza Atlantica Contro Il Disarmo Nucleare Unilaterale,", 1982 (Box-folder 136: 7)
  - Smoloskyp, 1976-1985 (Box-folder 136: 8)
  - Solidariat, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 136: 9)
  - Soviet Culture: An Information Series, 1956 February (Box-folder 136: 10)
  - Soviet Disinformation - What Is It? How Does It Work? Does It Matter?, circa 1985 (Box-folder 136: 11)
  - "Soviet Manipulation of Western News Media,", 1984 (Box-folder 136: 12)
  - "Soviet Military Power,", 1985 (Box-folder 136: 13)
  - Soviet Studies: A Quarterly Journal on the USSR and Eastern Europe, 1971 (Box-folder 136: 14)
  - Soviet Survey: An Analysis of the Cultural Trends in the USSR, 1957 (Box-folder 136: 15)
  - "Spiegel and Rudolf Augstein v. Sir James Goldsmith and Others: Where We Stand,", undated (Box-folder 136: 16)
  - "The Struggle for Our Hearts,", 1984 (Box-folder 136: 17)
  - Student newspapers and periodicals, 1957-1967 (Box-folder 136: 18)
  - "Summary of the World Broadcasts: Part 2, Eastern Europe (BBC),", 1980 (Box-folder 136: 19)
  - Supplemental clips, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 136: 20)
  - Survey Bulletin, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 136: 21)
  - Survey: A Journal of East and West, 1976 (Box-folder 137: 1)
  - Svědectví, 1972 (Box-folder 137: 2)
  - Translations on Cuba (U.S. Department of Commerce Office of Technical Services, Joint Publications Research Service), 1964 (Box-folder 137: 3)
  - Tribune, 1950-1961 (Box-folder 137: 4-7)
  - Tribune pamphlet series, undated (Box-folder 137: 8)
  - Unity, 1951 (Box-folder 137: 9)
  - Vantage Point, 1980 (Box-folder 137: 10)
  - Viewpoint, 1968 (Box-folder 137: 11)
  - "What They Say About Survey,", 1962 (Box-folder 137: 12)
  - Wiadomości, 1971 (Box-folder 137: 13)
  - "Wywiad z Bermanem,", 1985 (Box-folder 138: 1)
  - Wyzwolenie, 1985 (Box-folder 138: 2)
  - "The 1971 International Peace Academy Committe (IPAC) Transnational Training Project," (Box-folder 138: 3)
  - 13 Pismo Chrześcijańsko-liberalne, circa 1985 (Box-folder 138: 4)
  - Unidentified, 1964, 1974 (Box-folder 138: 5)
    Comprised of news clippings and two publications from an unidentified series. Articles titled, "Afro-Asian Solidarity and Sino-Soviet Dispute," and "Communist External Propaganda."
  - Newsprint, 1967 (Microfilm 138)
    Includes a microfilm reel comprised of copies of various Eastern European publications.
  - Oversize material, 1938-1973
    - Avanti, 1961 (Oversize-box 139: 1)
    - Critica Sociale, 1947 (Oversize-box 139: 2)
    - Demain, 1956 (Oversize-box 139: 3)
    - Die Internationale, 1948 (Oversize-box 139: 4)
    - Direct Action, 1947-1948 (Oversize-box 139: 5)
    - Document Sul Comunismo, 1968, 1971, 1973 (Oversize-box 139: 6)
    - Le Drapeau Rouge, 1947 (Oversize-box 139: 7)
    - Dziennik Ludowy, 1938 (Oversize-box 139: 8)
    - Europa Socialista, 1947 (Oversize-box 139: 9)
    - Forward, 1947 (Oversize-box 139: 10)
    - Freedom, Anarchist Fortnightly, 1947-1948 (Oversize-box 139: 11-12)
    - Freedom, Anarchist Fortnightly, 1949 (Oversize-box 140: 1-2)
    - Industrial Worker, 1948 (Oversize-box 140: 3)
    - L'Internazionale, 1946 (Oversize-box 140: 4)
    - Kronika, 1957 (Oversize-box 140: 5)
    - Labor Action, 1946-1947 (Oversize-box 140: 6-10)
    - Le Libertaire, 1947-1950 (Oversize-box 141: 1-4)
    - The Militant, 1947-1948, 1968 (Oversize-box 141: 5-7)
    - The New Leader, 1947 (Oversize-box 141: 8)
    - Nowe Sygnały, 1957 (Oversize-box 141: 9)
    - Praca, 1968 (Oversize-box 142: 1)
    - Socialist Appeal, 1946-1949 (Oversize-box 142: 2)
    - Socialist Leader, 1949-1950 (Oversize-box 142: 3)
    - The Socialist Standard, 1949-1950 (Oversize-box 142: 4)
    - Specchio, 1968 (Oversize-box 142: 5)
    - Der Tagesspiegel, 1948 (Oversize-box 142: 6)
    - Utunk, 1970 (Oversize-box 142: 7)
    - La Verite, 1946-1948 (Oversize-box 142: 8-10)
    - La Voix du Peuple, 1965, 1967, 1971 (Oversize-box 142: 11-13)
- Materials in Russian, 1950-1985
  - Agursky, Mikhail (Agurskii, Mikhail S., Агурский, Мелик Самуилович), "Ekonomicheskaia sistema vostoka i zapada,", 1973 December 4 (Box-folder 144: 1)
  - Agursky, Mikhail (Agurskii, Mikhail S., Агурский, Мелик Самуилович), "Rossiia kak mnogonatsional'naia strana,", circa 1973 (Box-folder 144: 2)
  - Amal'rik, Andrei, 1938-1980 (Амальрик, Андрей), "Ideologii v sovetskom obshchestve,", 1976 February 7 (Box-folder 144: 3)
  - Amal'rik, Andrei, 1938-1980 (Амальрик, Андрей), "Koleso ideologii,", 1976 February 7 (Box-folder 144: 4)
  - Amal'rik, Andrei, 1938-1980 (Амальрик, Андрей), open letter to the New York Times, undated (Box-folder 144: 5)
  - Amal'rik, Andrei, 1938-1980 (Амальрик, Андрей), "Prosushchestvuet li Sovetskii Soiuz do 1984 goda?,", 1969 June (Box-folder 144: 6)
  - Appeals and other writings of Soviet dissidents and political prisoners, 1974 (Box-folder 144: 7)
    Distributed by Leonid Rigerman.
  - Bakhmin, Viacheslav Ivanovich (Бахмин, Вячеслав), statement and supporting letter, 1985 March 29 (Box-folder 144: 8)
  - Belnikov, Arkadii Viktorovich (Бельников, Аркадий Викторович), untitled work on Soviet literature, 1968 June 20 (Box-folder 144: 9)
  - Chernyshov, Vasilii Ivanovich (Чернышов, Василий Иванович), "Obrashchenie k sovetskomu obshchestvu,", 1971 January (Box-folder 144: 10)
  - Daniel, Iulii, 1925-1988 (Даниэль, Юлий), poetry, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 144: 11)
  - Davydov, Georgii (Давыдов, Георгий), "Na puti k polnomu bezmolviiu,", undated (Box-folder 144: 12)
  - "Delo Siniavskogo i Danielia,", undated (Box-folder 144: 13)
    Table of contents only.
  - Discussion of the draft of the third volume of the History of Communist Party of the Soviet Union, undated (Box-folder 144: 14)
  - Dvadtsaty: vek, undated (Box-folder 144: 15)
    Table of contents to No. 5 of this samizdat almanac.
  - Fainberg, Viktor (Файнберг, Виктор), appeal, 1970 July (Box-folder 144: 16)
  - Geller, Mikhail,1922-1997 (Геллер, Михаил), "Vchera i segodnia v 'Krasnom Kolese' A. Solzhenitsyna,", undated (Box-folder 144: 17)
  - Grigorenko, Zinaida (Григоренко, Зинаида), open letter to the World Mental Health Society, 1971 February 2 (Box-folder 144: 18)
  - Grivnina, Irina (Гривнина, Ирина) i Neplekhovich, V. (Неплехович, В.), "Ia byla v Lefortove,", 1984 November 20 (Box-folder 144: 19)
  - "Grod prav cheloveka v Sovetskom Soiuze,", 1968 April 30 (Box-folder 144: 20)
  - Ianov, Aleksandr (Янов, Александр), "Na polputi k Leont'evu (Paradoks Solzhenistyna),", undated (Box-folder 144: 21)
  - "Interviu A. Solzhenistyna zapadnym korrespondentom,", 1972 March 30 (Box-folder 144: 22)
  - Ivinskaia, Ol'ga,1912-1995 (Ивинская, Ольга Всеволодовна), letter to Mr. Vigorell, 1971 November 2 (Box-folder 144: 23)
  - Kaverin, V. (Veniamin), 1902-1989 (Каверин, Вениамин), "Otkrytoe pis'mo Konstantinu Fedinu,", 1968 January 25 (Box-folder 144: 24)
  - Khodorovich, Tatiana Sergeevna (Ходорович, Татьяна Сергеевна), "Istoriia bolezni Leonida Pliushcha,", circa 1973 (Box-folder 144: 25)
  - Leaflets distributed to Soviet troops in Czechoslovakia, 1968 (Box-folder 144: 26)
  - Markish (Riabova, Liubov' Borisovna / Рябова, Любовь Борисовна), circa 1975 (Box-folder 144: 27)
    Untitled work on chemical weapons in the USSR.
  - Medvedev, Roy Aleksandrovich (Медведев, Рой Александрович), "Zagadki tvorcheskoi biografii Mikhaila Sholokhova,", 1974 December (Box-folder 144: 28)
    Preface only.
  - "Otvety Esenina-Vol'pina na voprosy V. Kola,", 1972 June (Box-folder 144: 29)
  - Panin, Dimitrii Mikhailovich, 1911-1987 (Панин, Димитрий Михайлович), Zapiski Sologdina, undated (Box-folder 144: 30)
  - Panin, Dimitrii Mikhailovich, 1911-1987 (Панин, Димитрий Михайлович), Zapiski Sologdina, undated (Box-folder 145: 1)
  - "Pusto kreslo,", 1970 (Box-folder 145: 2)
  - Radio Liberty research, 1959-1963 (Box-folder 145: 3)
    Bulletins and excerpts from the Soviet press.
  - Radio Liberty research - Samizdat reprints, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 145: 4)
  - Radygin, Anatolii (Радыгин, Анатолий), 1973 October (Box-folder 145: 5)
    Untitled memoir of life in Vladimir prison.
  - Sakharov, Andrei, 1921-1989 (Сахаров, Андрей), "Pamiatnaia zapiska,", undated (Box-folder 145: 6)
  - Schakovskoy, Zinaïda, princesse, 1906-2001 (Shakhovkaia Zinaida Alekseavna, Шаховская, Зинаида Алексеевна), undated (Box-folder 145: 7)
    Sketches of Russian literary life in Belgium and France.
  - Steindl, Johanna, undated (Box-folder 145: 8)
    Declaration, open letter, and other documents.
  - Turovskii, Feliks (Туровский, Феликс), "Problemy sudebnoi zashchity v SSSR,", 1977 June 21 (Box-folder 145: 9)
  - Unidentified author, "Khronika Baraslevskoi zony,", circa 1984 (Box-folder 145: 10)
  - Unidentified author, "Slovo natsii,", undated (Box-folder 145: 11)
  - Unidentified author, memoir of life as a political prisoner, undated (Box-folder 145: 12)
  - Valentinov, N. (Nikolai), 1879-1964 (Валентинов, Николай), "Opasnost' messianizma,", undated (Box-folder 145: 13)
  - Solzhenitsyn, Aleksandr Isaevich, 1918-2008 (Солженицын, Александр Исаевич), "Vserossiiskomu Patriarkhu Pimenu Velikopostnoe pis'mo,", 1972 (Box-folder 145: 14)
  - Zemtsov, Il'ia (Земцов, Илья), "Dialektika prestupleniia,", 1975 (Box-folder 145: 15)
  - Miscellany, 1950-1981, undated (Box-folder 145: 16)
    Includes materials in Bulgarian.
  - Tvardovskaia, V. A. (Valentina Aleksandrovna), 1931- (Твардовская, Валентина Александровна), "Otkrytoe pis'mo A. I. Solzhenitsynu,", 1975 June 24 (Box-folder 145: 17)